# Simar Pal Kalsi

ADDRESS TELEPHONE EMAIL

10 Overture Lane, Brampton, L6S6H9 416-919-5855

simarpal.kalsi@gmail.com

**OBJECTIVE** 

IT Professional with 4 Years of professional experience and 7years of programming experience in developing software solutions. Highly analytical approach to all problems faced. Successful in developing bespoke solutions, optimizing business procedures, processes and productivity. Highly inquisitive in nature with a history of thinking outside of the box for practical solutions.

EDUCATION

#### **West Humber CI**

High School Diploma 2017

# **York University**

Information Technology (Hons) 2018 - Present

WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **School**

Babysitting

### **Toronto Star**

Paper Delivery Teen

### **Computer Technician**

Worked as a freelance Computer Technician.

## **Amazing RC Store**

Worked as a seasonal RC technician and computer technician at the Amazing RC Store from January 2018 to July 2018

## Mech Solutions LTD.

Worked as technician and support staff from september 2018 to december 2018.

Worked as Technical Lead from Dec 2018 to MAY 2021.

#### **Cloud 3D Print**

Co-Founder and CTO of cloud 3d print from DEC 2018 to MAY 2021, Backend Developer from May 2021 to July 2023

- Worked on the serial communication module for connecting to multiple 3d printers asynchronously.
- Worked on Cloud based slicing engine and mesh file interpreters and subroutines for mesh file integrity check.
- Created documentation for IRAP proposals for the purposes of gaining funds from the Centre for Innovation.
- Researched patentable technologies and worked with patent lawyers in refining patents.
- Created and managed network infrastructure for various cloud service providers such as AWS and GCE.
- Created IOT software integration for our cloud based software on embedded systems.
- Worked with 3D printer manufacturers such as Kodak, Anet and Flashforge to improve their cloud infrastructure and for Kodak worked on an overhaul of their existing cloud based 3d printer infrastructure.

# **Rue's Productions (Internship)**

- Built backend system for image processing to allow the use of data science methods to analyze 2d images to allow use in the animation pipeline.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

AV crew

75th Toronto Scottish Regiment Royal Canadian Army Cadet Corps

Runnymede Robotics Team 1310 (Student and alumni mentor)

**York University Robotics Society** 

SKILLS AND ABILITIES

- Well versed in Java and knowledgeable in C++.
- Well versed in VM operations and cloud service providers such as AWS and Google Cloud
- Knowledge in working with Java application servers such as Tomcat and other Java EE technologies
- Familiar with TCP communication infrastructure and creating custom communication protocol standards.
- Very good understanding of everything 3d printer related, including hardware and software related to 3d printers.
- Knowledgeable operating systems such as Windows and Linux based operating systems such as various Debian based operating systems and Red-Hat based operating systems.
- Working on a robot has given me skills to work with various tools and machines such as the mill, lathe, band saw, drill press and various other machinery in addition to making complex measurements.
- Successfully built CNC machines (routers) to operational capacity and I have knowledge in generating toolpaths for 2.5d CNC machines.
- Familiar with Autocad Inventor and Fusion 360.
- Working knowledge of container technologies such as Docker and Kubernetes.
- Understanding of the patent process.
- Good cooperation skills.

CHIEV	EMENTS
]	Designed and manufactured my own 3d printer
,	Self taught programming.
]	Built my own computer and then added custom parts to it.
]	Built, designed and programmed the 5th best rated FRC robot in the world for the 2013 season.
]	learned various programming languages
,	Written custom 3d printer firmware

Making custom home automation software and hardware using open source technologies.

- Developing android applications and other programming applications.
- Taking an active part in FRC.
- Learning new Languages.
- Learning machining
- 3D printing